Southwest Folklore Center Pre-1980 Sound Disc Collection, 1931-1964
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- CanCan; Paludismo Agudo, Alfonso, Esteban, and Hermanos Dominguez, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana, S.A. Paludismo Agudo -- Lira de San Cristobal -- CanCan -- Lira de San Cristobal -- Record is damaged...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.328 (10in.)
- Himno Nacional; Historia del Himno Nacional de Guatemala, Santacoloma, German Boyer, Rafael Alvarez and J. Joaquin [Poma], 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Ministerio de Educacion Publica; Republica de Guatemala. Historia del Himno Nactional de Guatemala, narada por German Bayer Santacolona -- Himno Nacional, lerra de J. Joaquin [Poma], musica de Rafael Alvarez, Orq. y Coro de la Opera Nacional, dirreccion: Miguel Sandoval --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.329
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Swann, Wallace, Chub Parham, Wade Ward, Herbert Snoke, and Pete Steele, 1941; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax... 5 string banjo tunes: Old Joe Clark (Wade Ward) -- Chilly winds (Wade Ward) -- Cripple Creek (Herbert Snoke) -- Cole Creek March (Pete Steele)... Recorded by Alan Lomax and played by Wallace Swann and his Cherokee String Band, with square dancing, at Asheville Folk Festival, Asheville, N.C., 1941: John Henry... Recorded by Alan Lomax and played on the harmonica by Chub Parham, with clogging, at Asheville Folk Festival Festival, Asheville, N.C., 1941: The Train --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.330
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, May 12, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Library of Congress Recording Laboratory. Sing-tra-la-loo-loo (Casa Grande) -- He was only just a cowboy (Phoenix) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.331
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, May 12, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Library of Congress Recording Laboratory. Banks of the sweet Dundee -- Old man Crumble (Casa Grande) -- Under yonders tree (Casa Grande) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.332
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hilton, L.M., 1946; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Library of Congress Recording Laboratory. Recorded by Austin E. Fife and sung by L.M. Hilton of Ogden, Utah, 1946: Hard times -- Echo Canyon --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.333
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Watkins, Joseph H., 1946; 1 sound disc, analog, 78 rpm, 12 in.; Library of Congress Recording Laboratory. Recorded by Austin E. Fife and sung by Joseph H. Watkins, age 85, of Brigham City, Utah: Utah Iron Horse -- Tittery-irie-aye --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.334
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Trio Tariacuri con El Mariachi Vargas de Tecalitlan, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana, S.A. In Spanish... No puedo contigo (Teddy Fregosa) -- No hay derecho (Chucho Monge) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.335 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Trio Tariacuri, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana. In Spanish... Revancha (Hmos. Martinez Gil) -- Coplas de Michoacan (Juan Mendoza) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.336 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Lucha Reyes con la Orquesta de Armando Rosales, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana. In Spanish... La Ranchita (Joaquin Pardave) -- Juan Colorado (F. Bermejo - A. Esparza Oteo) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.337 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hermanas Padilla con Los Charros de Atotonilco, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Columbia. In Spanish... Por un amor (Gilberto Parra) -- Cocula (Esperon y Cortazor) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.338 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music, Hmos. Sanchez y Linares con guitares, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Decca. In Spanish.. Corrido de Joaquin Murrieta (Sanchez - Leal) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.339 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Los Tres Vaqueros, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana. In Spanish... La Bamba -- Pelea de gallos en San Marcos (Juan S. Garrido) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.340 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Trio Tariacuri con El Mariachi Vargas de Tecalitlan, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana. In Spanish... Ya semos dos (Cucho Monge) -- El Cupido (Son Jarocho) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.341 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Rubio y Martinez, Duo, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; New York, N.Y., Columbia Phonograph Company, Inc. Direction by A. Esparza Oteo... In Spanish... Mi gusto es (Alfonso Esparza Oteo) -- El Novel y deapuntado (arranged by Ernesto Rubio) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.342 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Tanco, Ernesto and Carlota Flores, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Camden, N.J., Victor Talking Machine Co. Los Marihuanoas - dialogo callejero (The Dope fiends) -- Mamorto el griago - dialogo callejero -- In Spanish...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.343 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Niles, John Jacob, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Camden, N.J., RCA Victor Division of Radio Corporation of America. Collected and arranged by J.J. Niles and [performed by] John Jacob Niles, mountaineer tenor, with dulcimer accompaniment: The Wife of Usher's Well -- The Death of Queen Jane --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.344 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Niles, John Jacob, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Camden, N.J., RCA Victor Division of Radio Corporation of America. Collected and arranged by J.J. Niles... Little Mattie Groves (John Jacob Niles, mountaineer tenor, with dulcimer accompaniment) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.345 (10in.)
- The Folk songs of Britain: Volume 5, The Child ballads, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Caedmon Records Inc. The Royal forester -- The Baffled knight -- Johnie Cock -- Robin Hood and Little John -- The Jew's garden -- The Battle of Harlaw -- The Four Maries -- The Gypsy laddie -- Georgie -- The Dowie Dens of Yarrow -- Glenlogie -- The Grey cock -- Henry Martin -- Lang Johnny More -- Willie's fate -- Our goodman -- The Farmer's curst wife -- The Jolly beggar -- The Auld beggarman -- The Keach in the creel -- The Golden vanity -- The Trooper lad --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.347
  Original Collector: Peter Kennedy and Alna Lomax
- Folk songs of Britain; Volume VI: Sailormen and Servingmaids, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Caedmon Records Inc. Paddy West -- The Liverpool packet -- The Green banks of Yarrow -- Our gallant ship -- The Alehouse -- Rosemary Lane -- Ratcliffe highway -- The Lowlands of Holland -- The Quaker -- Kishmul's gallery -- The Whale fishery -- The Grey silkie -- Warlike seamen -- The Boat that first brought me over -- The Handsome cabin boy -- The Unst boat song -- The Smacksman -- Sweet Willie -- The Campanero -- Andress Ross -- The Bold princess royal -- The Boatie rows -- Our ship is ready -- Nancy from Yarmouth --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.348
- Folk songs of Britain; Volume VIII: A Soldier's life for me, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Caedmon Records Inc. List, bonnie laddie -- Swansea barracks -- The Dying soldier -- Willie O'Reilly -- The Bonnet o' blue -- Recruiting song -- William Taylor -- Johnny Harte -- The Soldier and the sailor -- Bold General Wolfe -- Muddley barracks -- Handsome Polly -- The Deadly wars -- McCaffery -- Drink old England dry -- Prince Charlie Stuart -- Ny son Tim -- Napoleon Buon-le-Parte -- The Bonny bunch of Roses O -- Napoleon's dream -- The Forfar soldier --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.349
- Song plays and play party games for the elementary school, The Folkrafters, 1 sound disc, analog, [45 rpm], 7 in.; Newark, N.J., Folkraft Records. Performed by The Folkrafters, Frank L. Kaltman, director... Project supervised by Olga Kulbitsky, Hunter College, New York City... Round and round the village (Go in and out the window) -- Bridge of Avignon (French song play) -- A-hunting we will go (English song play) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.350 (7in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Briceno, Alcides y Jorge Anez, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Camden, N.J., Victor talking Machine Co. Performed by Alcides Briceno y Jorge Anez, [with orchestra]... Son popular: La Higuerita (The Honey girl, by Victor Mendoza) -- Cancion: La Pielera (The Railroad girl) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.351 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Cueto, M. and C. Mejia, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Camden, N.J., Radio-Victor Corp. of America. Performed by M. Cueto and C. Mejia, [with orchestra]... Corrido: El Vacilon (The High stepper, by J. Cordova Cantu) -- Corrido: El Ingrato (The Ungrateful one, arr. by J. Cordova --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.352 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Trio Calaveras, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Mexico, D.F., RCA Victor Mexicana SA. Performed by Trio Calaveras... Cancion: La Barca de oro (Abundio Martinez), [from the film] "Las Abandonadas" -- Cancion ranchera: Copitas de Mezcal (Chucho Palacios) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.353 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Chaves y Lugo, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; New York, Columbia Phonograph Company, Inc. Performed by Chaves y Lugo, [accompanied by guitars]... Corridos: El Lavaplatos, part 1 and part 2 (Jesus ?) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.354
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Lunsford, Bascom Lamar, Estelle Morris and Russ Pike, 1941; 1946; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Sung by Bascom Lamar Lunsford at Swannanoa, North Carolina, 1946, and recorded by Artus M. Moser: The Death of Queen Jane (child ballad) -- Wake, oh, wake, you drowsy sleeper... Sung by Estelle Morris of Franklin, Tennessee, and recorded by Artus M. Moser at Renfro Valley, Kentucky: The Knoxville girl (Development of "The Wexford girl", "Oxford girl", or "The Cruel miller", "The Wittam miller")... Sung by Russ Pike at Visalia, California, and recorded by Charles Todd and Robert Sonkin, 1941: The Railroader --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.355
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Paytiamo, James (Flaming Arrow) and Buck Lee, 1946; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Two social dances performed by James Paytiamo "Flaming Arrow", and recorded at Wisconsin Dells, Wisconsin, by University of Wisconsin Recording Project: Hopi corn song, "At the time of the new moon setting in the West, comes the rain. Four days later, plant the corn. Four days later comes the shoot. When the tassle ripens, I reap abundant" -- Hey - come my friend (Navajo)... Sung by Buck Lee, Clearfield, Utah, 1946, and recorded by Austin E. Fife: Billy Veniro, part I --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.356
- Golden slumbers: Lullabies from near and far, 1973; 1 sound disc, (34:26), analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Performers include: Oscar Brand, Pete Seeger, Jean Ritchie, Frank Cooke, Juanita Cascone, Ruth Welcome, Elizabeth Knight, Wallace House, Robin Roberts... All the pretty horses -- Twinkle, twinkle, little star -- Sleep, little one, sleep -- Raisins and almonds -- Go to bed first -- Dance to your daddy -- Rock-a-bye baby -- Hush lit'l baby -- Simba -- Bye, baby bunting -- Petit chat noir -- Golden slumbers -- Pretty boy in the country-o -- Bye'n bye -- Sleep, baby -- Coventry carol -- Cuc-a-nandy -- Kiowa lullaby -- Lalo -- Can ye sew cushions -- Who killed cock robin --Dance to your daddy -- Little Pierrot -- Sleep, baby, sleep --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.357
- Blues roots: Mississippi, 1966; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Compiled and edited by Samuel Charters... Canned heat blues (Tommy Johnson) -- Bif fat mama blues (Tommy Johnson) --- Big road blues (Tommy Johnson) -- Barbeque bust (Mississippi Jook Band) -- My grey pony (Joe Williams) -- Cigaret blues (Bo Carter) -- All around man (Bo Carter) -- I believe I'll dust my broom (Robert Johnson) -- Honeymoon blues (Robert Johnson) -- That lonesome train took my baby away (Charlie McCoy) -- Whiskey head man (Tommy McClennan) -- Bertha Lee blues (Robert Petway) -- Miss Louise blues (Sonny Ray Williamson) -- Until my love comes down (Sonny Ray Williamson) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.358
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Larry Richardson, Red Barker and the Blue Ridge Boys, 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Let me fall (Happy Smith) -- You left me so blue (Larry Richardson) -- More pretty girls than one (arr. Larry Richardson) -- I don't love nobody (P.D.) -- Paul and Silas (arr. Larry Richardson and Red Barker) -- John Henry (arr. Larry Richardson) -- Pain in my heart (Larry Richardson and Bob Osborne) -- Little Pal (arr. Larry Richardson) -- Liberty (P.D.) -- Wild over me (arr. Larry Richardson) -- Sad and lonesome day (arr. Larry Richardson and Red Barker) -- My home's across the Blue Ridge Mountains (arr. Larry Richardson and Red Barker) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.359
- Songs and dances of Great Lakes Indians, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Records and Services Corp. Ethnic Folkways Library. Musical selections by various performers include: Algonquians, Iroquis animal and war dances, Food spirit dances, and Future prospects... Tribes represented include Ojibwa, Ottawa, Meskwaki, Onondaga, Cayuga, Ontario, Huron and Seneca...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.360
- Spanish and Mexican folk music of New Mexico, 1952; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; [New York, N.Y.], Folkways Record & Service Corp. Ethnic Folkways Library. Recorded by J.D. Robb in New Mexico... Matachines dances (James Trujillo, Sam and Modesto Garcia) -- Huapango (Garcilian Pacheco) -- Entriega de novios (Felix Ortega) -- Polka (Librado Leyba and Eddie Ortiz) -- La Luna se va matiendo (Alfred Campos and Edwin Lobato) -- Cuatro caminos -- (Alfred Campos and Edwin Lobato) -- El Zapatero (Arthur L. Campa) -- Grasshopper waltz (Daniel Lopez) -- Cancion Ingles (Jacobo Maestas) -- Hymn of farewell (Congregation with violin and guitar) -- Corrido de Elena (Felix Ortega and Consuela Ortega) -- Jesusita (Vidal Valdez and Lupe Rodriguez) -- Para que me sirvo el vino (Daniel Lopez and Lupe Rodriguez) -- Trova del viego vilmas (Arvino Martinez) -- Cuna (Jacobo Maestras and Victor Frescas) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.361
- Music of La Raza, Vol. 1, Los Pinguinos del Norte, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Tradition Music Co. Produced by Chris Strachwitz and Rumel Fuentes... El Contrbando del paso (Juarez and Gaytan) -- Jacinto Trevino (Juarez and Gaytan) -- El Gallito (Rueben Juarez) -- Dos hermanos (Juarez and Gaytan) -- Mexico Americano (Rumel Fuentes) -- El Desperado (R. Juarez and H. Gaytan) -- Gregorio Cortez (Juarez and Gaytan) -- Benjamin Argumedo (Juarez and Gaytan) -- Carga blanca (Gaytan and Escalante) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.362
- Slim Critchlow, Cowboy songs: The Crooked trail to Holbrook, Critchlow, Slim, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Produced by Chris Strachwitz and Barry Oliver: The Crooked trail to Holbroook -- Borax Bill -- The Trail to Mexico -- Forty a month and found -- The Brazos River -- D-Bar-2 horse wrangler -- Windy Bill -- Goodbye Old Paint -- Bucking bronco -- I'd like to be in Texas -- The Buffalo skinner -- The Cowboy's lament -- Wild buckaroo -- Snag tooth Sal -- The Trusty lariat -- John Garner's trail herd -- Whiskey Bill -- The Last wagon --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.363
- Authentic cowboys and their Western folksongs, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; RCA Corporation. The Old Chisolm Trail ("Mac" McClintock) -- Powder River, let 'er buck (Powder River Jack and Kitty Lee) -- Following the cow trail (Carl T. Sprague) -- Zebra dun (Jules Allen) -- Bill was a Texas lad (J.D. Farley) -- Utah Carroll (Carl T. Sprague) -- There's a brown skin girl down the road (A.C. "Eck" Robertson) -- The Cowboy's dream (Jules Allen) -- When the work's all done this fall (Carl T. Sprague) -- Bucking broncho, my love is a rider (Mildred and Dorothy Good) -- Sam Bass ("Mac" McClintock) -- Tying a knot in the devil's tail (Powder River Jack and Kitty Lee) -- Texas Ranger (Cartwright Brothers) -- The Mormon cowboy (Carl T. Sprague) -- The Night guard (Jack Webb) -- Haunted hunter (Billie Maxwell) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.364
- Ellie Mao sings Chinese folk songs, Mao, Ellie and Anna Mi Lee, 1963; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; [New York, N.Y.], Folkways Records and Service Corp. The Sweeping wind -- In a far-away place -- The Funny old man -- Heartache -- A Festive song -- The Embroidered purse -- Digging potatoes -- Wu Ke tends the sheep -- Hanging red lanterns -- Lo-ho-ho -- The Nine-ring puzzle -- Clear is the river -- Kite-flying -- When the gardenias bloom -- Bean sprouts, scallions and garlic cloves --The Washerwoman -- My love is like a dragon in the sky -- The Mule driver's song -- A Guessing song -- Riding up the hill -- The Little birds -- Song of the wagon driver -- The Little swallow -- Majira -- The Happy fisherman -- The Little cabbage -- The Bamboo flute -- Flower drum song --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.365
- Lithuanian folk songs in the United States, 1955; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Record & Service Corp. Ethnic Folkways Library. Recorded by Dr. Jonas Balys... Sutartine (Choral round) -- Volungele (The Little golden oriole) -- Vidur Lauku (In the midst of the field) -- Nesigraudyk, merguzele (Do not be sorrowful little girl) -- Kaip as per zalia girela (Riding across a forest of green) -- Vai leidzia duoda (Oh, he is giving away) -- Oi as isejan an dvara (I go into the yard) -- Oi smutnas luidnas (Oh, how low sad and mournful) -- Vaikscio' mociute ( The Mother was walking) -- Vai broli (Oh, brother) -- Susapnavu dimna sapna (I dreamed a strange dream) -- Mergele grazi (Oh, beautiful girl) -- Oi stovi stovi (Oh there are standing) -- Oi klevi kleveli (Oh you little maple) -- Vai kaip as buvau (Oh, when I lived) -- Ulijana (Julia) -- SIle pusynai (In the conifer forest) -- Is karcmuzeles (Leaving an inn) -- Vaikseiojo tevulis (The Father was walking) -- Jau saulele teka (The Sun is rising) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.367
- Folk music of Ghana, 1964; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Record and Service Corp. Ethnic Folkways Library. Recorded in Ghana by Ivan Annan -- Akonodey -- Adaarve -- Ataa oblanyo -- Simpa -- Agbaja -- Agbaja -- Kumi 'na gyaemi -- Gome (Mr. Jacobson) -- Gome (Janja) -- Akorah anumah -- Abosuan -- Asafo -- Asaaye -- Kolomashie --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.368
- Lappish joik songs from Northern Norway, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Record & Service Corp. Ethnic Folkways Library. Recorded by Wolfgang Laade and Pieter Christensen... Various folk songs by various performers from Northern Norway...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.369
- Jazz, Vol. 10: Boogie woogie and jump, 1953; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; [New York], N.Y., Folkways Records & Service Corp. Records from the collection of Frederic Ramsey, Jr..... Boogie woogie: Jim Jackson's jamboree, part 1 -- Jim Jackson's jamboree, cont'd. -- Hastings Street -- St. Louis blues -- Honky tonk train -- Brown skin gal -- Yancey stomp -- Jump and Kansas City: Let 'em jump -- Toby -- Froggy bottom -- Boogie woogie -- Hootie blues -- Lester leaps in -- Dickie's dream --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.370
- The Unquiet grave: American tragic ballads, Summers, Andrew Rowan, 1952; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York City, N.Y., Folkways Record & Service Corp. Performed by Andrew Rowan Summers accompanying himself on the dulcimer: The Unquiet grave -- Searching for lambs -- Pretty Sally -- The True lover's farewell -- The Cruel brother -- Geordie -- At the foot of Yonders Mountain -- The House carpenter --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.371
- Pre 1980 Folk music. Selections, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; From paper insert, "The two ladies & the man with the concertina from the Jewish Cultural Center"...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.372
- Pre 1980 Folk music. Selections, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Recorded [in the] Wisconsin Dells by University of Wisconsin Recording Project, 1946... Performed by Margaret Eagle (age ca. 40) and Phyllis Lewis (age 10): Eagle dance. Zuni -- Dance song, "When the dance is over you must wait for me; I will take you home in my barrow [on my burro]. When the dance is over you must wait for me; I will take you home in my flivver." -- Lullaby. Zuni... Performed by James Paytiamo (Flaming Arrow): Wedding sosngs. Acoma... From the Tusque Pueblo: Buffalo dance song -- 2nd Buffalo dance song --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.373
- Pre 1980 Folk music. Selections, Hinton, Sam and Pleaz Mobeley, 1947; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Recorded by Duncan Emrich and George Steele, Washington, D.C., 1947... Sung by Sam Hinton of La Jolla, California: Mary Hamilton (The Four Marys) -- Katy Cruel... Recorded by Artus M. Moser at Renfro Valley, Kentucky, 1946, and sung by Pleaz Mobeley of Manchester, Kentucky: My parents raised me tenderly --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.374
- Pre 1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Amy Hancock, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Safford, AZ. Recorded by F. [Frances] Gillmor... I'll hang my heart on a willow tree and off to the wars again -- God pity Bessie, the drunkard's love child -- God pity Bessie, the drunkard's love child -- Tis of a young sailor with courage stout and bold --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.376
- Pre 1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Amy Hancock, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Safford, AZ. Recorded by [Frances] Gillmor... I should dearly love to marry -- As I was walking one morning in May -- As I was walking one morning in May --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.377
- Pre 1980 Folk music. Selections, Baird, Amy Hancock, 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Safford, AZ. Recorded by Frances Gillmor -- The Hunter winds his bugle horn -- Green Bill -- I was born in Boston -- Willie Gray -- My grandmother lived on yonder little green --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.378
- Pre-1980 Interview, Upplegger, Dr. [Francis] (1867-1964), March 25, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; San Carlos, AZ. Byrd Granger interviews Dr. Upplegger on Apache place names on March 25, 1956 in San Carlos, AZ....; SWF PRE1980.1/D.383
  Original Collector: Byrd Granger
- Pre-1980 Interview, Upplegger, Dr. [Francis] (1867-1964), March 25, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; San Carlos, AZ. Byrd Granger interviews Rev. Upplegger on Apache names on March 25, 1956 in San Carlos, AZ....; SWF PRE1980.1/D.384
- Pre-1980 Interview, Upplegger, Dr. [Francis] (1867-1964), March 25, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Byrd Granger interviews Dr. Upplegger on March 25, 1956 regarding the Hopi place names... Do not transcribe...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.386
- Pre-1980 Interview, Upplegger, Dr. [Francis] (1867-1964), March 25, 1956; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; Byrd Granger interviews Dr. Upplegger on March 25, 1956 regarding the Hopi place names... Do not transcribe...; Byrd Granger; SWF PRE1980.1/D.387